<exercises>

   

   <exercise>
           <name>High Knees</name>
           <gender>Male</gender>
           <gender>Female</gender>
           <bodyPart>Cardio</bodyPart>
           <equipment>
               <item>Bodyweight</item>
           </equipment>
           <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OAJ2SFeVNy4</video>
           <icon>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwIcons/highknees.jpg</icon>
           <animation>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwGif/highKnees.gif</animation>
           <time>30</time>
           <whatItDoes>A high-energy cardio burst that strengthens the legs, improves heart rate, and enhances coordination and flexibility in the hip flexors.</whatItDoes>
           <executionSteps>
               <step>Stand with your feet hip-width apart.</step>
               <step>Lift your right knee toward your chest as high as possible.</step>
               <step>Immediately switch and lift your left knee while dropping the right.</step>
               <step>Continue alternating knees at a running pace, pumping your arms to maintain momentum.</step>
           </executionSteps>
           <commonMistakes>
               <mistake>Leaning too far back to compensate for leg height.</mistake>
               <mistake>Landing heavily on your heels; stay light on the balls of your feet.</mistake>
           </commonMistakes>
       </exercise>
   
   <exercise>
           <name>Jumping Jacks</name>
           <gender>Male</gender>
           <gender>Female</gender>
           <bodyPart>Cardio</bodyPart>
           <equipment>
               <item>Bodyweight</item>
           </equipment>
           <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Pxr4xOrhNk</video>
           <icon>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwIcons/jumpingjack.jpg</icon>
           <animation>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwGif/jumpingjack.gif</animation>
           <time>30</time>
           <whatItDoes>A classic full-body movement that improves cardiovascular endurance, coordination, and metabolic rate.</whatItDoes>
           <executionSteps>
               <step>Stand with your feet together and arms at your sides.</step>
               <step>Jump up while spreading your legs wider than shoulder-width and clapping your hands above your head.</step>
               <step>Jump again to return your feet together and bring your arms back to your sides.</step>
               <step>Maintain a steady, rhythmic pace throughout the set.</step>
           </executionSteps>
           <commonMistakes>
               <mistake>Landing with locked knees; keep a slight bend to absorb impact.</mistake>
               <mistake>Using "half-arms" instead of full range of motion over the head.</mistake>
           </commonMistakes>
       </exercise>
   
   <exercise>
           <name>Lunges</name>
           <gender>Male</gender>
           <gender>Female</gender>
           <bodyPart>Lower Body</bodyPart>
           <equipment>
               <item>Bodyweight</item>
           </equipment>
           <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L8V6SByM580</video>
           <icon>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwIcons/lunges.avif</icon>
           <animation>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwGif/Lunges.gif</animation>
           <time>30</time>
           <whatItDoes>Develops lower body strength and stability by targeting the quadriceps, hamstrings, and glutes while improving balance.</whatItDoes>
           <executionSteps>
               <step>Stand tall with your feet hip-width apart and hands on your hips.</step>
               <step>Take a large step forward with one leg and lower your hips until both knees are bent at approximately 90-degree angles.</step>
               <step>Ensure your front knee is directly above your ankle and your back knee is hovering just off the ground.</step>
               <step>Push off your front foot to return to the starting position and repeat with the other leg.</step>
           </executionSteps>
           <commonMistakes>
               <mistake>Allowing the front knee to extend past the toes, which puts stress on the joint.</mistake>
               <mistake>Losing balance by stepping in a straight line; keep your feet hip-width apart like they are on train tracks.</mistake>
           </commonMistakes>
       </exercise>
   
   <exercise>
           <name>Abdominal Crunches</name>
           <gender>Male</gender>
           <gender>Female</gender>
           <bodyPart>Core</bodyPart>
           <equipment>
               <item>Bodyweight</item>
           </equipment>
           <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xyd_fa5zoEU</video>
           <icon>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwIcons/crunches.avif</icon>
           <animation>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwGif/crunches.gif</animation>
           <time>30</time>
           <whatItDoes>Isolates the abdominal muscles to improve core strength and endurance.</whatItDoes>
           <executionSteps>
               <step>Lie on your back with knees bent and feet flat on the floor.</step>
               <step>Place your hands lightly behind your head without pulling on your neck.</step>
               <step>Engage your core to lift your shoulders toward your knees.</step>
               <step>Lower slowly back to the start and repeat with control.</step>
           </executionSteps>
           <commonMistakes>
               <mistake>Pulling on the neck instead of using the abs.</mistake>
               <mistake>Lifting the entire back off the ground.</mistake>
           </commonMistakes>
       </exercise>

       <exercise>
           <name>Plank</name>
           <gender>Male</gender>
           <gender>Female</gender>
           <bodyPart>Core</bodyPart>
           <equipment>
               <item>Bodyweight</item>
           </equipment>
           <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v25dawSzRTM</video>
           <icon>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwIcons/plank.webp</icon>
           <animation>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwGif/plank.gif</animation>
           <time>30</time>
           <whatItDoes>Strengthens the entire core, including the abs, obliques, and lower back, while building stability.</whatItDoes>
           <executionSteps>
               <step>Get into a forearm plank position with your elbows under your shoulders.</step>
               <step>Form a straight line from your head to your heels.</step>
               <step>Squeeze your glutes and pull your navel toward your spine.</step>
               <step>Hold the position steady without letting your hips sag or hike up.</step>
           </executionSteps>
           <commonMistakes>
               <mistake>Allowing the lower back to arch (swayback).</mistake>
               <mistake>Dropping the head or shoulders.</mistake>
           </commonMistakes>
       </exercise>

       <exercise>
           <name>Wall Sit</name>
           <gender>Male</gender>
           <gender>Female</gender>
           <bodyPart>Lower Body</bodyPart>
           <equipment>
               <item>Wall</item>
           </equipment>
           <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y-wV4Venusw</video>
           <icon>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwIcons/wallsit.jpg</icon>
           <animation>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwGif/wall%20sit.gif</animation>
           <time>30</time>
           <whatItDoes>Builds exceptional isometric endurance in the quadriceps and glutes.</whatItDoes>
           <executionSteps>
               <step>Lean your back flat against a sturdy wall.</step>
               <step>Walk your feet out and slide down until your thighs are parallel to the floor.</step>
               <step>Keep your knees aligned over your ankles at a 90-degree angle.</step>
               <step>Maintain pressure through your heels while holding the position.</step>
           </executionSteps>
           <commonMistakes>
               <mistake>Positioning feet too close to the wall, causing knee strain.</mistake>
               <mistake>Not squatting deep enough to reach parallel.</mistake>
           </commonMistakes>
       </exercise>
       
       <exercise>
               <name>Push-Ups</name>
               <gender>Male</gender>
               <gender>Female</gender>
               <bodyPart>Upper Body</bodyPart>
               <equipment>
                   <item>Bodyweight</item>
               </equipment>
               <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IODxDxX7oi4</video>
               <icon>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwIcons/push-up.jpg</icon>
               <animation>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwGif/pushups.gif</animation>
               <time>30</time>
               <whatItDoes>Builds functional upper body strength in the chest, shoulders, and triceps while stabilizing the core.</whatItDoes>
               <executionSteps>
                   <step>Place hands on the floor slightly wider than shoulder-width apart.</step>
                   <step>Lower your body until your chest nearly touches the floor while keeping your elbows at a 45-degree angle.</step>
                   <step>Push through your palms to return to the starting plank position.</step>
                   <step>Maintain a straight line from your head to your heels throughout the move.</step>
               </executionSteps>
               <commonMistakes>
                   <mistake>Flaring elbows out to 90 degrees, which stresses the shoulders.</mistake>
                   <mistake>Letting the hips sag or the lower back arch.</mistake>
               </commonMistakes>
           </exercise>

           <exercise>
               <name>Push-Up and Rotation</name>
               <gender>Male</gender>
               <gender>Female</gender>
               <bodyPart>Upper Body</bodyPart>
               <equipment>
                   <item>Bodyweight</item>
               </equipment>
               <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yp69mDNo8o0</video>
               <icon>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwIcons/pushupside.avif</icon>
               <animation>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwGif/pushuprotation.gif</animation>
               <time>30</time>
               <whatItDoes>Combines chest strength with rotational core stability and shoulder balance.</whatItDoes>
               <executionSteps>
                   <step>Perform a standard push-up.</step>
                   <step>As you push back up, shift your weight to one hand and rotate your body open.</step>
                   <step>Reach your top arm toward the ceiling, forming a "T" shape with your body.</step>
                   <step>Return to the starting position and repeat, alternating sides.</step>
               </executionSteps>
               <commonMistakes>
                   <mistake>Rotating only the shoulders instead of the entire torso and hips.</mistake>
                   <mistake>Moving too fast and losing control of the balance phase.</mistake>
               </commonMistakes>
           </exercise>

           <exercise>
               <name>Side Plank</name>
               <gender>Male</gender>
               <gender>Female</gender>
               <bodyPart>Core</bodyPart>
               <equipment>
                   <item>Bodyweight</item>
               </equipment>
               <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BFOyHDlY2UE</video>
               <icon>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwIcons/sideplank.webp</icon>
               <animation>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwGif/sidePlanks.gif</animation>
               <time>30</time>
               <whatItDoes>Isolates the oblique muscles and improves lateral spinal stability and hip strength.</whatItDoes>
               <executionSteps>
                   <step>Lie on your side with your elbow directly under your shoulder and feet stacked.</step>
                   <step>Lift your hips off the ground until your body forms a straight line from head to feet.</step>
                   <step>Keep your core tight and your neck neutral, looking straight ahead.</step>
                   <step>Hold the position, then switch to the other side halfway through the set.</step>
               </executionSteps>
               <commonMistakes>
                   <mistake>Allowing the bottom hip to drop toward the floor.</mistake>
                   <mistake>Leaning the top shoulder forward rather than keeping it stacked vertically.</mistake>
               </commonMistakes>
           </exercise>
           
           <exercise>
                   <name>Squats</name>
                   <gender>Male</gender>
                   <gender>Female</gender>
                   <bodyPart>Lower Body</bodyPart>
                   <equipment>
                       <item>Bodyweight</item>
                   </equipment>
                   <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aclHkVaku9U</video>
                   <icon>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwIcons/squat.jpg</icon>
                   <animation>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwGif/squats.gif</animation>
                   <time>30</time>
                   <whatItDoes>Builds functional strength in the lower body, specifically the quads, hamstrings, and glutes, while improving hip mobility.</whatItDoes>
                   <executionSteps>
                       <step>Stand with feet shoulder-width apart and toes slightly pointed out.</step>
                       <step>Lower your hips back and down as if sitting into an invisible chair.</step>
                       <step>Keep your chest up and ensure your knees stay aligned with your toes.</step>
                       <step>Drive through your heels to return to a standing position.</step>
                   </executionSteps>
                   <commonMistakes>
                       <mistake>Allowing the knees to cave inward during the descent.</mistake>
                       <mistake>Lifting the heels off the ground, shifting weight too far forward.</mistake>
                   </commonMistakes>
               </exercise>

               <exercise>
                   <name>Step-Ups</name>
                   <gender>Male</gender>
                   <gender>Female</gender>
                   <bodyPart>Total Body</bodyPart>
                   <equipment>
                       <item>Chair</item>
                   </equipment>
                   <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dQqApCGd5Ss</video>
                   <icon>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwIcons/stepup.webp</icon>
                   <animation>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwGif/stepups.gif</animation>
                   <time>30</time>
                   <whatItDoes>Increases lower body power and balance while providing a significant cardiovascular boost.</whatItDoes>
                   <executionSteps>
                       <step>Stand in front of a sturdy chair or step.</step>
                       <step>Place your entire right foot onto the chair and push through the heel to lift your body up.</step>
                       <step>Bring your left foot up to join the right on the chair.</step>
                       <step>Step back down carefully, starting with the right foot, and alternate legs.</step>
                   </executionSteps>
                   <commonMistakes>
                       <mistake>Pushing off the floor with the bottom foot instead of using the top leg's strength.</mistake>
                       <mistake>Using an unstable surface that could tip over.</mistake>
                   </commonMistakes>
               </exercise>

               <exercise>
                   <name>Triceps Dips</name>
                   <gender>Male</gender>
                   <gender>Female</gender>
                   <bodyPart>Upper Body</bodyPart>
                   <equipment>
                       <item>Chair</item>
                   </equipment>
                   <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0326dy_-CzM</video>
                   <icon>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwIcons/triceps.jpg</icon>
                   <animation>biplovkhatri.com.np/GymApp/hwGif/triceps.webp</animation>
                   <time>30</time>
                   <whatItDoes>Targets the triceps on the back of the arms and the front of the shoulders for improved pushing strength.</whatItDoes>
                   <executionSteps>
                       <step>Sit on the edge of a chair with hands next to your hips.</step>
                       <step>Slide your hips off the chair while supporting your weight with your arms.</step>
                       <step>Lower your body by bending your elbows until they reach about 90 degrees.</step>
                       <step>Press back up until your arms are straight but not locked.</step>
                   </executionSteps>
                   <commonMistakes>
                       <mistake>Letting the elbows flare out to the sides; keep them tucked back.</mistake>
                       <mistake>Moving the hips too far away from the chair, which strains the shoulders.</mistake>
                   </commonMistakes>
               </exercise>

</exercises>
